<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swarm Intelligence | Xinhao Xiang</title>
    <link>https://shanexiangh.github.io/xinhao-xiang/category/swarm-intelligence/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shanexiangh.github.io/xinhao-xiang/category/swarm-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Swarm Intelligence</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {2021-2022} Xinhao Xiang. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shanexiangh.github.io/xinhao-xiang/media/icon_hu97fa295c981cf3619a2662561ff5587f_2164830_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Swarm Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://shanexiangh.github.io/xinhao-xiang/category/swarm-intelligence/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative Motion and Multi-target Searching Methods of Swarm Robotics</title>
      <link>https://shanexiangh.github.io/xinhao-xiang/research/collaborative-motion-and-multi-target-searching-methods-of-swarm-robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shanexiangh.github.io/xinhao-xiang/research/collaborative-motion-and-multi-target-searching-methods-of-swarm-robotics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advised by Prof. Yuhui Shi and Prof. Jian Yang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding&lt;/strong&gt;: This project is awarded 2020 &amp;ldquo;Climbing Plan&amp;rdquo; Special Fund for Science and Technology Innovation Cultivation of College Students in Guangdong Province (Funding code: PDJH2020b0522, Percentage: 10/400+, Fund received: RMB 40,000, 12/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employed the strategy of collaborative motion and multi-target searching of swarm intelligent robots under the condition of decentralized topology architecture and limited sense of perception and info-communication ability;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established the corresponding simulation and experiment system using mobile robot simulation platforms like MATLAB and Webots as well as real robots like E-Puck and TurtleBot to verify the effectiveness of relevant methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposed a new potential field (PF) based multi-robot movement strategy for it, where Brain Strom Optimizing (BSO) algorithm plays an important role in contributing to local area potential field, and applied the strategy to detect the pollution source;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the same map condition, my strategy performs a generally higher performance on multi-target searching in MATLAB multi-robot environment, compared to other classic multi-robot movement strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1AiipKyoe0Nugu_niXZT5wEC-sZssI0FT/view?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Undergraduate Thesis&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;“Collaborative Multitarget Searching of Robotic Swarms Based on PF and BSO Algorithm”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assisted to propose an exploration enhanced Robotic Particle Swarm Optimization (E2RPSO) method for multi-target searching problems on robotic swarms;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proposed method modifies the third item in the RPSO as an additional attraction term, not only enables the robot to avoid collisions but also guides the swarm to search unexplored regions as much as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This operation increases the swarm’s task-specific (top-down) diversity, making the system cover a broader search area and avoid falling into local optimums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/complexity/2020/8863526/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication: Jian Yang, Ruilin Xiong, Xinhao Xiang, and Yuhui Shi, “Exploration Enhanced RPSO for Collaborative Multitarget Searching of Robotic Swarms”, Complexity, vol. 2020, Article ID 8863526, 12 pages, 2020.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assisted to propose a BSO-based collaborative searching framework for swarm robotics called Robotic BSO;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The simulation results show that the proposed method can simulate the BSO’s guided search characteristics and has an excellent prospect for multi-target searching problems for swarm robotics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007%2F978-3-030-78811-7_16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication: Jian Yang, Donghui Zhao, Xinhao Xiang, and Yuhui Shi, “Robotic Brain Storm Optimization: A Multi-target Collaborative Searching Paradigm for Swarm Robotics”, Advances in Swarm Intelligence, ICSI 2021, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 12690, Springer, Cham.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
